scoutbook.com 2019-05-09

# Scoutbook - Privacy Policy

Protecting your private information is our priority. This Statement of Privacy applies to www.scoutbook.com and Scoutbook.com and governs data collection and usage. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to Scoutbook.com include www.scoutbook.com and Scoutbook.com. 

www.scoutbook.com may provide information and unit-management features for BSA Scouting Programs. This includes advancement tracking as appropriate. From time to time there may be additions and changes to videos, forums, directories and online/offline references. 

By using the Scoutbook.com website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. 

**Collection of your Personal Information**  
Scoutbook.com may collect personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, birthday and gender. Scoutbook.com may also collect anonymous demographic information. We may gather additional personal or non-personal information in the future. 

Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by Scoutbook.com. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Scoutbook.com website. 

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Scoutbook.com's public message boards, photos, videos or comments this information may be collected and used by others. 

Scoutbook.com encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Scoutbook.com so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Scoutbook.com is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Scoutbook.com website. 

**Use of your Personal Information**  
Scoutbook.com collects and uses your personal information to operate its website(s) and deliver the services you have requested. 

Scoutbook.com may share your personal information including contact numbers, address and email with others in your chartered organization (connected accounts). If you create connected accounts this information may also be shared with your chartered organization. 

By creating an account on Scoutbook.com you may appear on our secure members only global list of users, so others can find and add you to their roster. Your name, city and your current Scouting position(s) may be shown for others to identify you better. 

Scoutbook.com may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Scoutbook.com and its affiliates. Scoutbook.com may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. 

Scoutbook.com does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. 

Scoutbook.com may share data with trusted partners to help perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Scoutbook.com, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. 

Scoutbook.com may keep track of the websites and pages our users visit within Scoutbook.com, to determine what Scoutbook.com services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Scoutbook.com to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a subject area. 

Scoutbook.com will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Scoutbook.com or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Scoutbook.com; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Scoutbook.com, or the public. 

**Use of Cookies**  
The Scoutbook.com website may use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Scoutbook.com pages, or register with Scoutbook.com site or services, a cookie helps Scoutbook.com to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Scoutbook.com website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Scoutbook.com features that you customized. 

You can accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Scoutbook.com services or websites you visit. 

**Security of your Personal Information**  
To secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure, Scoutbook.com uses the following:  
256-bit SSL encryption 

When personal information is transmitted to other websites, it is protected using encryption, such as the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol. 

**Children Under Thirteen**  
Scoutbook.com complies with The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We do not allow children under the age of 13 to create an account without the approval of a parent or guardian. 

If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use this website. If you are a parent and you have questions regarding our data collection practices, please contact us using the information provided at the end of this Statement of Privacy. 

If you are a parent who wishes to allow your child under the age of thirteen to have his/her own Scoutbook.com login account, you must first, (1) create your own Adult account, then (2) add your child to your account. These special family linked accounts allow parents to monitor the online activity of their child on this website. Scoutbook recommends all children under the age of 18 have a parent linked account. 

**Disconnecting your Scoutbook.com Account from Third Party Websites**  
If you connect your Scoutbook.com account to third party accounts then BY CONNECTING YOUR SCOUTBOOK.COM ACCOUNT TO A THIRD-PARTY ACCOUNT, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE CONTINUOUS RELEASE OF INFORMATION ABOUT YOU TO OTHERS (IN ACCORDANCE WITH YOUR PRIVACY SETTINGS ON THOSE THIRD-PARTY SITES). IF YOU DO NOT WANT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU, INCLUDING PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION, TO BE SHARED IN THIS MANNER, DO NOT USE THIS FEATURE. You may disconnect your account from a third-party account at any time. Users may learn how to disconnect their accounts from third-party websites by visiting their "My Account" page. Users may also contact us via email. 

**Opt-Out & Unsubscribe**  
We respect your privacy and give you an opportunity to opt-out of receiving announcements of certain information. Communications from Scoutbook.com that are system use related or are sent by units to which the member is affiliated are assumed to be communications for which there is no opt-out. 

**Changes to this Statement**  
Scoutbook.com will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Scoutbook.com encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Scoutbook.com is protecting your information. 

**Contact Information**  
Scoutbook.com welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Scoutbook.com has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Scoutbook. 

**Contact Us**

Scoutbook.com  
Boy Scouts of America  
PO Box 152079  
Irving, Texas 75015-2079

Email Address:  

Updated January 1, 2019
